Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco and my name is Katherine
and today at English Pod we have a lesson
for you about small talk. That's right
we continue with our series about
short casual conversations you may have
with your friends somebody you haven't
seen in a long time or maybe even a
co-worker. That's right so in today's
dialogue we're going to listen to two
people who work in the same building.
They're going to talk a little bit about
travel right Marco. Yep we're gonna talk
a little bit about recommending a place
to go on vacation maybe Europe and so
we're gonna have some great phrases as to
speaking of this topic
very briefly with a friend.
All right let's listen
to today's dialogue.
Hey Michelle good to see you. Are you
at lunch? Oh hi Jim. No I just got back. I
thought you were on vacation now.
No I wish I was. I just got back from Spain
actually. Oh wonderful. Have you been
there before or was it your first time?
My first time I've traveled around Europe
a lot but this is my first time to Spain.
It was amazing and the weather was just
beautiful no rain and just sun sun sun.
I'm so jealous of you. I've
never been anywhere in Europe.
I've always dreamed of traveling
around and seeing the sights. Well I really
recommend Spain. You really should go.
Anyway it's been great to catch up but
I must be going. This is my floor. Speak
again soon I hope. For sure. Take care.
All right we're back so now let's
take a look at some of the language on
language takeaway. Language takeaway.
All right in language takeaway we've got a
couple of words and phrases for you.
The first one is I just got back so to get
back from somewhere Marco. That's right
Jim just got back from Europe and that when
you say I just got back is I recently or
very recently returned from somewhere.
That's right to get back from somewhere
means to return from that place.
So in this dialogue Jim just got back from
Spain. Michelle just got back from lunch.
This means to return from somewhere.
That's right so it can be a place
not only a country but it can be for
example the office. I just got back from
work or I just got back from football
practice that's why I'm very sweaty. Right
so this obviously means that you are
now not in the same place where you just
got back from. Now I'm from America I
went to Spain on vacation and I just got
back from Spain. That means I'm in
America again. Yeah exactly you're not
still in Spain. No. All right so that's
for our first word now let's go on and
Michelle said oh I'm so jealous of you.
All right jealous is an adjective and a
very very common one you can use in a
many different circumstances it means to
want what someone else has. That's right
so in this case Michelle is jealous that
Jim went on vacation so she wishes
she could go on vacation. That's right I'm
so jealous of you or if you see someone
who has a new pair of shoes and you
like the shoes because you don't have
them you can say I'm so jealous I love
your shoes. That's right so you say I
am jealous or if you are jealous of a
person you say I am jealous of you.
And so they were ending their conversation
and Jim said you know what it's been
great to catch up with you. All right this
is a really important phrase to catch up.
It means two different things and we're
gonna talk about one meeting here today.
To catch up with someone like to talk
to them about what they've been
doing recently means to learn about their
life because maybe you haven't talked
in a long time. That's right so maybe
you haven't seen your friend in two
years and you go out for dinner to catch up
to talk about what has happened in
your life recently. That's right or you can
if you see a friend on the street and
you know that you haven't seen him or
her in a long time you can make a date
to catch up. So hey Marco I haven't seen
you in months. Let's catch up sometime
soon. That's right and and that means to
share information and to find out
how you have been recently. Exactly.
All right now when he was getting out of
the elevator he said this is my floor now
we know floor but my floor what is
my floor your floor whose floor right this
doesn't make much sense does it
well actually floor here means that this is
the floor that I work on or the floor
that I live on. It means the place I'm
going to. Right so we know floor the the
ground beneath her feet in a building but
in this case we're talking about one
of the levels of a building so maybe the
sixth floor. That's right so if I'm in
my apartment building in the elevator I
can say oh stop the elevator this is
my floor I want to get off the elevator.
Right this is where this is where I live.
All right so a lot of great stuff there
when we take a break and
listen to the dialogue again.
Hey Michelle good to see you. Are you
at lunch? Oh hi Jim. No I just got back. I
thought you were on vacation now. No I wish
I was. I just got back from Spain actually.
Oh wonderful. Have you been there before
or was it your first time? My first time.
I've traveled around Europe a lot
but this is my first time to Spain it was
amazing and the weather was just
beautiful no rain and just sun sun sun.
I'm so jealous of you. I've never been
anywhere in Europe. I've always dreamed of
traveling around and seeing the
sights. Well I really recommend Spain.
You really should go. Anyway it's been
great to catch up but I must be going.
This is my floor. Speak again
soon I hope. For sure. Take care.
All right we're back so now let's take
a look at four key phrases on fluency
builder. Fluency builder.
So there are some keys to these small
conversations and they are definitely
the phrases the first time we have here
is good to see you. So Jim says hey
Michelle good to see you. That's right so
we've chosen this phrase because it's
very casual and very common to use as a
polite way of saying hey how are you
good to see you? I'm actually showing you
that I'm happy that I am talking to you.
So this is a very flexible phrase you
can say at the beginning of a conversation
when you just see someone and hey
Marco good to see you or at the end
you can say it was very good to see you.
I hope to see you again soon. That's right
so maybe you can use it at the beginning
if you just begin to talk to someone
or if you're saying goodbye you can say
well you know what I have to go
now but it's been good to see you.
So very flexible phrase. That's right
that's right now when Michelle thought that
Jim was on vacation Jim said no
no I wish I was. All right I wish I was I
thought you were on vacation so she
thought that he was still on vacation in
Spain and he says well I'm not because
you know here I am but I wish I was I
wish I was in Spain right now because
Spain is so nice. That's right so it may
seem a little bit strange but it's
actually completing the idea so and
basically we're using the verb to be
because that's the question are are you
on vacation? No I wish I was on vacation.
So that means he's not but he wants to be.
That's right okay so now he
actually had to get going and he
used this exact phrase he said I must
be going. I must be going now remember
this as a phrase this is a good way
to end a conversation maybe you have
to go to work maybe you have your
kids at home you have to take them
somewhere so you say I'm really
sorry I must be going but let's see each
other again soon. That's right so you
are politely ending the conversation
you are lightly saying I
can't talk to you anymore
I must be going now but it's been
great to talk to you. That's right very
polite so remember this one
it's better than I'm going now.
We don't say that. Yeah or I have to
go but you can say I have to go but
it's nice saying oh you know what I really
like talking to you but I must be going.
And Jim also finished by saying we will
speak again soon and Michelle said for sure.
For sure now Americans
particularly love to say this phrase
for sure means yes or I agree or
definitely. Right you can use it as an
interjection so if I say a Katherine am
I going to see you later on today yeah
for sure for sure there we go.
So you're saying yes absolutely
definitely for sure. So Marco my birthday
is Friday night are you going to come to
the party? Oh for sure I wouldn't
miss it for the world all right so
that's all we have for today. Why
don't we review everything we've taken a
look at now and listen to
the dialogue one last time.
Hey Michelle good to see you.
Are you at lunch? Oh hi Jim
no I just got back I thought you were
on vacation now. No I wish I was I just
got back from Spain actually. Oh wonderful
have you been there before or was it
your first time? My first time I've
traveled around Europe a lot but this is my
first time to Spain it was amazing and
the weather was just beautiful no rain
and just sun sun sun. I'm so jealous of
you. I've never been anywhere in Europe.
I've always dreamed of traveling
around and seeing the sites.
Well I really recommend Spain. You really
should go. Anyway it's been great to catch
up but I must be going. This is my floor.
Speak again soon I hope. For sure take
care. All right so this was another part
of our small talk series as you can see
very short but very useful language
used to talk very briefly with someone.
It always happens you meet somebody
at the elevator or you just want to talk
very quickly. Yeah but you don't
want to talk about anything that's too
personal like someone's politics
or their religious beliefs or their
children because maybe you don't
know them very well. So these are really
great topics to talk about like
business trips or vacation or the weather.
English speakers love to talk about these
when they don't know someone that well.
That's right that's right. So if
you have any questions or any
comments about this lesson or
you want to suggest any other topics
you can find us at EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you all there. Bye!